<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Pasindu's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-19T21:54:53+05:30</updated>
  <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Pasindu De Silva]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[pasindud@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Finch]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/finch/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-19T19:30:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/finch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>*<a href="https://github.com/pasindud/Finch">Github</a></p>

<p>Ideamart SMS and USSD Testing Framework. When building a large sms App it is kind of hard to keep track of or functions because
mostly it is one big file there you need something some test to run and make sure you havent broken anything</p>

<hr />

<p><img src="http://s13.postimg.org/rbyudk0pz/tests.png" alt="Finch UI" /></p>

<h3>Note</h3>

<ul>
<li>Test.php and testserver.php must be on the same folder.</li>
<li>Goto index.html and link test.php to run the tests.</li>
<li>App server URL is the test.php</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<!--more-->


<h4>Tests</h4>

<pre><code>    //Create Finch

    $opt=new Finch(App Url,App ID);

    Eg-:
        $opt=new Finch('http://localhost/dialog/listener.php', 'APP_000001');


    // Create SMS Tests
     $optsms-&gt;assertmatchsms(Test Name,Message Sent,Message Expected);

     Eg-:
        $optsms-&gt;assertmatchsms("First Message","hi start","This message is sent only to one user");


    // Create USSD Tests
    $optsms-&gt;assertmatchsms(Test Name,Message Sent,Message Expected,ussdoperation);

    Eg-:
        $optussd-&gt;assertmatchussd("Main Menu",'123','1. One 2. Two 99. Exit','mo-init');


    // Create Custom Tests
    $optussd-&gt;customTest(Test Name , Test Message, Test True for passes );

    Eg -:
        $optussd-&gt;customTest("Test DB","Test Works","false");
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Idea Group Simulator]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/idea-group-simulator/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T18:44:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/idea-group-simulator</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="http://idea-sim.herokuapp.com/">Online Group Simulator</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pasindud/idea-simulator-web">Online Group Simulator Github</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pasindud/ideamart-group-simulator">Local Group Simulator</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I was developing a chat app for ideamart but ran into difficulty when trying to test on the existing ideamart
simulator which is kind of only good for apps where only one user is involved
so I built a multi user simulator, where you can create phones and send message from those to the app.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>To test your multiusers ideamart apps on the web <a href="http://idea-sim.herokuapp.com/">idea-sim.herokuapp.com</a>,
this project is on <a href="https://github.com/pasindud/idea-simulator-web">Github</a></p>

<p>on the online version to test your app</p>

<ul>
<li>Click on config and App listener url and save it</li>
<li>Then in your app set the server url as <a href="http://idea-sim.herokuapp.com">http://idea-sim.herokuapp.com/sms/some number</a></li>
<li>Then you can send create a phone</li>
<li>Then send a message and watch the log</li>
</ul>


<p>To test you multiusers ideamart apps locally <a href="https://github.com/pasindud/ideamart-group-simulator">go here</a> and download it and run it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NodeBB]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/nodebb/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T18:14:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/nodebb</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pasindud/nodebb">GitHub</a></li>
</ul>


<p>NodeBB simple forum NodeJS powered, this was my first project on nodejs was trying to learn nodejs for long time but was hard, I found this great sample good i cannt remember right :( which awesome I understood everything from it.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>I used mysql as the database, jugglingdb with Jugglingdb Mysql Adapter as the ORM i tried many other things as well but they were hard to get working.</p>

<p>I used socket.io with <a href="https://github.com/CodeSeven/toastr">https://github.com/CodeSeven/toastr</a> to send broadcast notifications of new posts and post replies.</p>

<p>All together I used the following modules to build this</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.mysql.com/">Mysql</a> &ndash; Database</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/1602/jugglingdb">jugglingdb</a> &ndash; Database ORM</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/jugglingdb/mysql-adapter">jugglingdb-mysql</a> &ndash; Jugglingdb Mysql Adapter</li>
<li><a href="http://expressjs.com/">Express.js</a> &ndash; Node.js Web Framework</li>
<li><a href="http://jade-lang.com/">Jade</a> &ndash;  Templating Engine</li>
<li><a href="http://momentjs.com/">Moment.js</a> &ndash; Lightweight Date Library</li>
<li><a href="http://twitter.github.com/bootstrap/">Twitter Bootstrap</a> &ndash;  CSS Framework</li>
<li><a href="http://socket.io/">Socket.io</a> &ndash; Library for realtime applications</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/caolan/async">Async</a> &ndash; Module used to work asynchronous JavaScript</li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/CodeSeven/toastr">Toastr</a> &ndash; Library to pop notification</li>
</ul>


<h4>Installation</h4>

<pre><code>git clone git://github.com/pasindud/nodebb
cd nodebb
npm install -d
node app
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Geek Me ( About Me )]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/geek-me/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-17T18:05:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/geek-me</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<ul>
<li><a href="https://github.com/pasindud/aboutme">GitHub</a></li>
<li><a href="http://my-aboutme.herokuapp.com/pasindu">Project Site</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I needed to make a aboutus page which was quick and we didn&rsquo;t have to login, where
I could just change stuff in .json file which change the about. I wanted to take my NodeJS skills to a test drive so I built Geek Me.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Geek Me is About Me in Geek style you have a config file called yourname.json which stores all your details and you can send a pull request. I it currently hosted on Heroku.</p>

<p>Following is the template for a yourname.json file.</p>

<pre><code>{
  "name"         : "Your Name",
  "location"     : "you location",
  "discription"  : "about u",       

  "style":{
    "content_style":"",     // styling the container holding all your data
    "custom": "",           // all custom styles for your page
    "theme" : "default"     // theme name       
  },


  // Social website links   
  "links": {
    "facebook"  : "your facebook username",
    "linkedin"  : "your linkedin id no",
    "twitter"   : "you handle",
    "googleplus": "google+ id no",
    "github"    : "github username"
  },

  // Other links can be personal sites , blogs etc.
  "other_links":[{
      "url"       : "your url",
      "caption" : "Subject of the url",
      "icon"      : "icon to be shown beside the url" 
    }
  ]
}
</code></pre>

<p>You can also save the generated file and upload it to your site as I have done <a href="http://www.pasindu.us">www.pasindu.us</a></p>

<p> Todos</p>

<ul>
<li>Add other themes</li>
<li>Generate a ZIP file which can be downloaded and uploaded to a different site</li>
</ul>


<p>Hope This was Interesting</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[c ascii text]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/c-ascii-text/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-16T00:26:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/c-ascii-text</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://github.com/pasindud/c_ascii_txt">Github</a></p>

<pre>                     _             _        
                    (_)           | |       
 ____   _____   ___  _  ____    __| | _   _ 
|  _ \ (____ | /___)| ||  _ \  / _  || | | |
| |_| |/ ___ ||___ || || | | |( (_| || |_| |
|  __/ \_____|(___/ |_||_| |_| \____||____/ 
|_|                                         </pre>


<p>I have been searching for a C Ascii text generator written in C, but did
not find any light weight files to do it,</p>

<!--more-->


<p>So I made my own function set to do
I during which I can across some challengers being a web programmer mostly
because in C text cannot be compared as we normally do,
there is another function
to do it strcmp(text1,text2) in the string.h library, It is simple and can be extended without any
problem. Anyone can add series of text patterns.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fun with facebook]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/fun-with-facebook/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-29T01:54:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/fun-with-facebook</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had previously used the facebook api for general purpose but not like what I did today. I wanted to compile a statistics on group members.</p>

<h4>I wanted to calculate</h4>

<ul>
<li><p>How much the member liked &ndash; eg &ndash; [ I like your post  ]</p></li>
<li><p>How much the users post was like &ndash;   [ You like my post  ]</p></li>
<li><p>How much messages the user posted on the group &ndash; [ Me posting a new message on the group ]</p></li>
<li><p>How much comments did the member post &ndash; [ Me  commenting on your post ]</p></li>
<li><p>How much members posted comments on the users post &ndash; [ You  commenting on my post ]</p></li>
<li><p>How much pictures have you posted to the group &ndash;[ Me posting a picture to the group ]</p></li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<p>Before the start I it was bit trick parsing the JSON file with multiple titles.</p>

<p>&hellip;</p>

<p>I used facebook&rsquo;s graph API to do this, to get group post you must give the app access to your group permission , if you give it, it is fair to say the app knows what
ever you or any of the members of the group dose, and it takes only one person to let it in.</p>

<h3>It has access  &ndash;</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>What you post on the group.</p></li>
<li><p>What other members post on the group.</p></li>
<li><p>The comments you post.</p></li>
<li><p>The comments other members post.</p></li>
<li><p>Pictures you post.</p></li>
<li><p>Pictures others post.</p></li>
<li><p>Your likes.</p></li>
<li><p>Other members likes.</p></li>
</ul>


<h4>And Many Many More !!! It knows what ever you do better than you.</h4>

<ul>
<li>First I got the member list of the group and stored easy no pro !</li>
<li>Then got all pictures posted on the group and there links.</li>
<li><p>Then messages posted on the group which is fairly easy to parase.</p></li>
<li><p>But then you have comments that is the not so easy !!
It has many level of parasing , first you have the message you post on and the who posted it.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>This is how I parased it , this gives the name of the who posted.</p>

<pre><code>    ['feed']['data']['ori_message']['comments']['data']['comment']['from']['name']
</code></pre>

<p>Below is the php source to parase it.</p>

<pre><code>     if(array_key_exists('comments', $data)==false)
     {
        // This display the comment ID which was deleted by the user
        // It is just a reference there is no messae there.

        echo " Error comments ".$post_id." ".$data['updated_time'];

    }
    else
    {
                $comment_wrapper2=$data['comments']['data'];

                    foreach ($comment_wrapper2 as $data2) {

                                $user=$data2['from']['name'];
                                $user_id=$data2['from']['id'];

                                $created_time=$data2['created_time'];
                                $like_count= $data2['like_count'];
                                $message= $data2['message'];
                                $com_id= $data2['id'];

                    }
    }
</code></pre>

<p>Due to many complication I did not get the details on who liked your comment ( may be there is someone who always like your comment will never know still )
if i implemented that also them json would look something like this.</p>

<pre><code>    ['feed']['data']['ori_message']['comments']['data']['comment']['from']['name']['data']['like']['from']['name'] 
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li><p>After that was over I had to fetch data and count them.</p></li>
<li><p>Everythings there was easy except comments because when your counting the number of comments for example comments on my post, you cannot add the number of comments
I post on my comment. Query that data is bit hard to accomplish.</p></li>
<li><p>I am trying to built it so that any one can get access to that data and view the stats and may be make there own stats.</p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[share-it]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/share-it/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-27T23:32:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/share-it</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is suddenly came up with when my friends were on a quest to share thee movies and tv shows they have.
I may have only taken me 1 hours to develop but took some time designing
Share it is a online movie / tv series sharing site. In context you may guess that when I say online sharing site you may think it is
uploading videos but it is not.
When you share it you share the name, season you got which you have downloaded, brought or stolen from someone.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>You may think so what is the use of sharing if you can&rsquo;t download
it or watched. So if that is the question, I can ask you Why bother downloading and spend your bandwidth
[ those days slt usage limit was no limit but now you have ]
when you can ask your friend for the video either telling him to bring it on a pen drive or got to his home.</p>

<p>The site will show a list of video your friend you can select what you.
No longer do you have to worry about downloading a camera copy of a movie and next day find out that you best friend has a
HD copy of the same thing.</p>

<p>Share it url : <a href="http://pasindu.us/mov">http://pasindu.us/mov</a></p>

<p>Go ahead and share want you got [ you will may be able to get a couple of bugs while sharing ]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[online-snippets]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/online-snippets/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-25T23:31:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/online-snippets</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Currently I am developing a online snippet safe form where you can type code online Zor maybe copy and save it online, the code editor is online is
fullscreen therefore there is distractions.I be using the laravel framework to do this project which is a really great framework and the Eloquent ORM with
it&rsquo;s relationship functionalities makes life easy to the programmers to work with.</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Features</h3>

<ul>
<li>Login</li>
<li>Profile</li>
<li>Public Codes</li>
<li>Private Codes</li>
<li>Online Code Editor</li>
<li>Quick save without needing to login</li>
</ul>


<p>Hope fully I will be getting a chance to learn laravel more and more.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[start-blogging]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.pasindu.us/start-blogging/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-25T01:50:00+05:30</updated>
    <id>http://blog.pasindu.us/start-blogging</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I been looking for a good blogging platform for a time now which is light wight with all options need and hopefully without any database attachted to.</p>

<p>Present blogging platforms like wordpress, druple and others are very capable and extensive they are also a bit of a pine to maintain
due to database and the large code base. Jekyll is a great blogging system after it uses a templating system markdown so you don&rsquo;t have
to type those tedious
html tags no longer. Jekyll also powers github pages and many other sites.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>During this search i also found ruhoh which is also really great the slight best things is that it has a good cmd and help cmd when considering with
 jekyll i think which has non. You can also create post on using the cmd. I knew ruby coding was bit crazy
 &ldquo; one function can be done in many ways &rdquo; online when I looked at the gem file I found it out.
For instance to find the length of the array you can do length , size or count. Apart from that understand the code than php which i really have worked
with. I did a bit of a hacking to the ruhoh and customized the CLI , added some things to the help yml to include posts list, post count and some
others, I also added some parameters to be passed when creating new posts.</p>

<p>There was a issues on ruhoh to get the posts count I fixed it also, don&rsquo;t really know how good the code is but end of the day it works.
I am still bit trying to deploy ruhoh on heroku
hopefully there will be some good documentation in the future</p>

<p>Github &ndash;:  <a href="https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
